(reel whirring)
(somber music)
(thunder rumbling)
(people cheering)
(upbeat music)
(crowd applauding and cheering)
(door opens)
- This next one's
for you, Father.
- Oh, I'm not here
for the celebrations.
- No, he's here with
his collection plate!
(crowd laughing)
- Well now, Tom, a penny
less spent on drink
wouldn't do you any
harm, now would it?
(crowd laughing)
And it is the day of our
patron saint after all.
- All the more reason
for a drink, then!
Won't you join us, Father?
Oh, go on, just the one perhaps.
(crowd laughs)
(door closes)
(ominous music)
- Where is she?
I said where is she?
- Ah, who is it you'd
be after there, Darragh?
- You know damn
well who I'm after!
My Nora, that's who!
- Can't say that I've seen her.
Anybody else?
- I know she's been foolin'
around with that Micky Doyle.
And I know this is
where he comes drinkin'!
- Really now, Darragh,
we've not seen her.
Now won't you please
just calm down?
- I'll calm down when my wife's
home where she oughtta be!
- Now come on, we all
know what day it is, son.
It's the day of St. Patrick,
when the light of Christian
kindness first came
to our emerald island.
Surely it's a day for
forgiveness, and kindness.
A day when we can
all come together
and remember what
the good Lord said.
(Nora moaning)
- Nora!
(Nora gasps)
- [Micky] Darragh, it's
not what it looks like.
- Micky Doyle.
- No. Please.
(Darragh grunts)
(Micky screams)
(Nora gasps)
- Nora?
Nora!
Where is she?
- Gone.
Out the door,
running for her life.
- Then get out of my way.
- We can't let you go
after her, Darragh.
- You'll do as I
damn well tell ya!
- It's murder what
you've done up there.
I know you had good
cause and all, but-
- Good cause?
So you knew what she was up to?
Suppose you all knew, did ya?
That she's carryin'
on behind me back?
- Remember Darragh, what the
Good Lord said about adultery.
Let he who is without
sin cast the first stone.
- Suppose you were
the first to know!
You know all the
town's sins, don't ya?
Thanks to that confession box.
Did she tell you where?
And when?
And how many times?
- That's enough, Darragh!
Maeve!
(Maeve heavy breathing)
Put down that blade.
- You'll have to
take it from me.
- You think we don't
have the guts, Darragh?
- I think you won't
have them for long.
- It doesn't have to
be this way, Darragh!
- I think it does, Tom.
It's clear to me now.
Y'all been laughing
at me behind me back.
Thinkin' me a fool.
Well now you're going to let
me walk out of here like a man.
Or else I'll kill
every damn one of you!
(gun fires)
(Darragh grunts)
(somber music)
(woman screaming)
(upbeat rock music)
(plane rumbling)
(upbeat music)
- Here ya go, four special
Saint Patrick's Day cocktails!
One for you.
What's your name?
- Daisy.
- A pretty name for
a pretty girl, eh?
- And one for you.
- Oh, wait, wait, wait.
- So you girls all
from England, then?
- Not all of us.
But we're all over
here from London.
- Here for the Saint
Patrick's Day weekend, eh?
- I thought we could soak up
some traditional Irish culture.
- Well you've come
to the right place.
The finest bar in Dublin,
or so they tell me.
- What exactly is in this?
- Ah, coconut rum, pineapple,
and a whole lotta'
green food coloring.
- This is a traditional
Irish drink?
- Sure!
We've been selling
these for years.
So, are you gonna introduce me
to your lovely friends, here?
- Sure.
This is Kendra,
Sian and Leena.
What's your name?
- Connor.
(customers screaming)
Look, I gotta get
back over there.
Maybe I'll catch you
girls later, yeah?
- Did you see that?
He spent the whole
time staring at Daisy
and barely glanced
at the rest of us.
- I can't help it if you
guys don't make an effort.
- Make an effort?
Look at this suit!
- We're not all
here on a manhunt.
- I wonder what
time he gets off?
- Come on, Sian's right.
We're here for a girls' weekend,
probably the last one, right?
- Yeah, I've got a job
lined up in Switzlerland
after the summer.
- I'll probably go
back to Manchester.
- My PhD is almost done.
I guess I'll be
heading back home, too.
How about you, Sian?
- I'm not too sure yet.
- Well, anyhow, we need to
make the most of this trip.
Everyone raise a glass.
- [All] Happy Saint
Patrick's Day!
- Ah, wait, let
me get a picture!
- Hurry up, Daisy, my
arm's gonna fall off.
- Smile!
(camera clicks)
Oh.
- [Leena] I've been thinking.
- I'm fine. Thanks.
- This is everyone's first
time in Ireland, right?
And some of us have been having
a bit of a hard
time of it lately.
So what are we
doing sitting here
with these stupid cocktails?
Let's go see Ireland!
We came here to soak
up some Irish culture,
not to go drinking in bars.
- I think drinking in
bars is the Irish culture.
- You know what I mean.
Like if you want to get drunk,
let's at least go
find a real Irish pub.
Somewhere with a little history.
This place could be
anywhere in London or LA.
- [Daisy] I like it here.
- You like the guy
serving the drinks.
- I just love his
accent, it's so sexy.
- Daisy, every one here
has the same accent.
- [Daisy] No, his is different.
- On that note, look
who's coming back.
- Sorry about that.
Can I get you girls
anything else?
- We were wondering if you
had any recommendations
for places we could
go visit around here?
- Leena would like to get
drunk somewhere more historic.
- That's not what I said!
- She's our resident historian.
PhD in dusty old books.
- My family has Irish ancestry.
- You've no idea how
many Americans say that.
Especially on Saint
Patrick's Day.
- I'm serious.
It's the whole reason why I
wanted to go study in Britain.
- Britain and Ireland
aren't exactly
the same thing, y'know.
- I know that.
You know what?
I'm going to the bathroom.
- Be a shame if you all left.
Anyway, I wouldn't
exactly be doing my job
if I told you to go an' drink
somewhere else, would I?
- Are you exactly
doing your job now?
- So what's this, a
girls' weekend away?
- [Daisy] We do a trip
like this every year.
- This one was Leena's idea.
She wanted to reconnect
with her Irish ancestry.
- Look, I can't help ya.
I'm not a Dubliner.
I came up from from
Kilkenny for the weekend.
You know there's a lot of bar
work going this time of year,
lots of tourists, if
you know what I mean?
- Like us?
- I wouldn't exactly
call you tourists.
"Visitors", more like.
- What's the difference?
- Visitors we welcome.
Tourists, we just
take their money.
- What sort of welcome
would you give me?
- A warm one, definitely.
- Uh, can I get past?
- Sorry, I didn't
mean to startle you.
It's just I couldn't
help but overhear
that you're looking for
a place with history.
- Right.
- Well, it just so happens
I've got a place nearby.
Been in my family
for generations.
- Um, what kind of place?
- A tavern, I guess
they would've called
it in the old days.
Been standing on the same
spot for about 200 years.
Probably one of the oldest
buildings in Dublin.
- And, um, it's not some
kind of tourist trap?
- What do you mean?
- Like it costs a bunch
of money to get in,
and then the drinks
are like 50 bucks each?
- No, no, no.
This is a real
traditional place.
Got like these
beautiful oak tables.
And real Irish whisky
behind the bar.
- And it's nearby?
- A few streets away.
(glass breaking)
(men shouting)
- What was that?
- Ah, don't worry about that.
This is not a rough place.
Believe me, I've
worked in a few.
So you girls are all
studying together?
- We're all at the same
uni, but different subjects.
- Pharmacology.
- Gender Studies.
- What about you?
- Maybe I'll tell you later.
What time do you get off?
- 12:30.
Maybe if I get your number,
we could get together?
- Yeah sure.
I'll text you.
- [Connor] Oh, I
don't have my phone.
I'll go to the bar and
get a piece of paper.
- Come on guys, let's go!
- Go where?
- I've just met this guy who's
got the most amazing place!
We have to see it!
- We've only just got here.
Can we not just
finish our drinks?
- Yeah, this place
is fine, Leena.
- It's so boring.
Look at these cheap
decorations and fake drinks.
We didn't come all the
way to Dublin for this.
- I wouldn't mind
going somewhere else.
- Shall we take a vote on it?
- Fine.
Just give me a few minutes.
(upbeat music)
- Look at them all
staring at her.
How does she do it?
- It's because she's beautiful.
- [Leena] What is she doing?
- She's gone after that guy
that brought us the drinks.
- Can we just wait
a few more minutes?
(glass shattering)
(men shouting)
- Come on guys, let's go.
(glass shattering)
The guy's over there,
his name's O'Reilly.
(men fighting, shouting)
- Shit!
(mellow music)
(thunder rumbling)
- Oh, this is amazing.
How old did you say it was?
- Couldn't tell you.
I know it's been a tavern
for at least 200 years.
Could have been something
else before that.
- These bricks
were made by hand.
Definitely older than 200 years.
- You're some kind of expert?
- Yeah.
Leena's our history buff.
- Not an expert on
bricks, exactly.
My thesis is on Crime
and Punishment in
Britain and Ireland,
1800 to 1868.
- 1868, huh?
Why stop there?
- Well, they banned
all public executions,
so it kind of gets less
interesting after that.
- Do you really have to do that?
It's really embarrassing.
- Do you know how
much bacteria exists
on a high-touch
surface like a table?
If you'd looked
down a microscope
and seen them all milling
about, you'd do the same thing.
- What did you
say this was, oak?
- Yeah.
Everything here is original.
Nothing's been updated.
Well, apart from the plumbing.
- So is there anything to drink
or are we just gonna
sit here in the dark?
- Didn't you say something
about Irish whiskey?
- Yeah, I did.
(door opens, closes)
(ominous music)
- What's up?
- I wanted to send you
guys that picture we took
before, but it's not working.
There's like no signal.
- There'll be plenty
of time for that later.
Look at this place,
it's so cool.
- You're not seriously
suggesting we spend
our evening here?
- Oh, why not?
It's awesome.
- Well, it's a little creepy.
- And definitely unsanitary.
- Come on.
Where's your sense of adventure?
- Well, I'm plenty adventurous.
- We all know that.
- Actually, it kinda
reminds me of this place
this guy once took me to.
It was this old abandoned house.
- [Kendra] What for?
- You know what for.
I mean, come on, I was 15.
Just somewhere to go.
It's not like I have
my own apartment.
- How old was the guy?
- Don't make it sound sleazy.
It's my first time actually.
- [Kendra] Are you going
to tell us the whole story?
- I will, if you will.
- I wasn't there.
- No, I mean, your
story, your first time.
- [Kendra] I suppose
I could be persuaded.
- [Daisy] Go on, you first then.
- [Kendra] No, you.
- It was, it was your idea.
- You started it.
- Okay.
So this guy was a bit older
and he would hang around at
the entrance to our school.
- Oh God, I don't
want to hear this.
- So he had this big flashy car
and he would just sit
there, revving the engine.
So we were all super impressed.
And then one day he offered
to give me a ride home.
- That sounds like the
start of a horror movie.
- No, he was fine.
He didn't do anything bad.
Well, I mean, the
sex was a bit bad,
but I didn't know any
better back then so.
- Okay, can we just
please change the subject?
- Okay.
Then it's Kendra's turn.
- I never said I would tell.
- Yeah, you did.
Come on.
Don't be shy.
- W-What about Sian,
shouldn't she have a turn?
- What?
- [Kendra] When was
your first time?
- Um...
- [Kendra] You do have
a first time, don't you?
- You know what kind of stories
we should be telling
in a place like this?
Ghost stories.
I know a great one.
It's based in Ireland too.
There's this castle
in County Antrim,
built in the 17th century,
and there was this
woman that lived there
named Lady Isabella Shaw.
Isabella's husband, James,
was a drunk and a tyrant.
In his eyes, her
only purpose in life
was to give him a male heir,
someone to carry
on the family name.
After many years of misery,
Isabella finally
became pregnant.
But to her husband's
horror, the baby was a girl.
He was so enraged that
he took the child away
and locked Isabella
in the highest tower
as cruel punishment
for her failure.
Isabella was so distraught
that she stepped through the
window in that high tower
and leapt to her death.
From that day on,
James began to experience
strange phenomena,
mysterious knocking on doors,
footsteps on the stairs,
creaking floorboards.
(door closes)
(all gasp)
- How are you doing?
Real traditional Irish
whiskey, distilled right here.
This will put hairs
on your chest.
(Leena coughs)
- My God, this is like
drinking pure alcohol.
- Nah, nah, not at all, no.
50%, no more.
Well, maybe just a...
- Are these glasses clean?
- Well, if there's any
bacteria in these glasses,
I guarantee you the
whiskey'd kill them.
- So what happened?
- What?
- You know, in the castle?
- Oh, it was totally haunted.
- Did Isabella ever
get her revenge?
- I don't know.
It's just a thing I read
on the flight over here.
- Oh, what a terrible story.
- What's going on
here then, huh?
Telling some ghost
stories, are we?
- Trying to.
I guess it's not my thing.
- I got one for you.
Real good one.
True as well.
If you wanna hear it.
- That'd be great.
- It happened 200 years ago.
This very day, St. Patrick's Day
and a farm yard laborer,
Darragh O'Donoghue,
came looking for his wife.
(ominous music)
- Where is she?
- Well he found her in
the arms of another man,
young Micky Doyle.
(Darragh grunts)
(Nora gasps)
- [Mickey] Darragh, it's
not what it looks like.
(Darragh snarls)
- Now Darragh was known
for being a violent man.
When he gazed down
at his lady wife,
an anger erupted inside
of him so deeply,
would've even scared the bejesus
out of the most bravest of men.
Now unluckily for Micky,
Darragh had in his
hand his trusty scythe,
fresh from a hard day's
labor in the fields.
(Darragh snarls)
Before the two of them even
had a chance to beg for mercy,
he went to work.
(Darragh grunts)
(Mickey screams)
(Nora gasps)
(both screaming)
He hacked and slashed, like
some kind of rabid animal.
(Darragh grunts)
(Mickey screams)
Didn't even notice Nora
slipping out the
back door, escaping.
Went downstairs.
Waiting for him,
was an angry mob.
- Where is she?
- Gone.
Out the door.
Running for her life.
- He convinced himself
they knew all about
what his wife was
doing behind his back
and that they'd
kept it from him.
So he went after
them with his scythe,
and they shot him
down with pistols.
(Darragh grunts)
(gun fires)
- Ah!
- The last words to
come out of his lips
were him screaming vengeance
for everyone that
done him wrong,
most viciously on his wife Nora.
Well, they were a good
Catholic community
or so they believed anyway,
but the events of
that terrible night
were an almighty scandal.
Even the parish
priest was there.
So they decided to keep
it secret and tell no one.
They gathered up all the
weapons and they hid them away,
and then Darragh
himself, they buried him
where he fell beneath
the floorboards.
The murder weapon,
that big old blade,
well, they buried it with him.
- Wait a second, I know a
thing or two about Catholicism.
They wouldn't have buried
his body under a tavern,
it's unconsecrated ground.
- Like I said, the parish
priest was in on it as well.
So he said a few
words for a blessing
and they guessed that would
do as consecrated ground.
- Does it work that way?
- Well they believed it did, but
I don't believe it all myself.
You see, they say that
Darragh O'Donoghue
never did rest in peace.
And they say once a year
on St. Patrick's night,
he rises up from
his shallow grave,
and they say, you can hear
his shuffling footsteps.
The screeching of
the blade behind him
as he drags it along
the floorboards.
And worst of all the
sound of his voice,
that ghastly voice, screaming
out to his unfaithful wife.
"Nora!"
- And the place
where this happened,
it wouldn't happen
to be right here?
- Oh, that's what they say.
- Imagine if there's a dead
body underneath our feet.
- Well, it was hundreds
of years ago, right?
It'd just be dry
old bones by now.
- Come on guys,
it's just a story.
He probably tells it
to all the tourists.
Isn't that right, Mr. O'Reilly?
(thunder rumbling)
- Weather's pretty
bad out there.
You ladies got
somewhere to stay?
- Yeah, we booked
a couple of rooms.
What was that place, Sian?
You booked it.
- I can't get the page up.
I don't think
there's any signal.
- That's not gonna work here.
Solid walls, two foot thick.
- I think it's called
"Cullenswood Road."
- Oh, that's a bit
of a way that is,
you'll never get across
there at this hour at night.
All the cabs will be booked up.
- What do you suggest?
- Well, I have a couple
of rooms upstairs.
I meant to turn this
place into a guest house,
but I never finished the work.
You're welcome to
stay the night.
- Is there even
anywhere to wash?
- Aye.
There's a shower room
upstairs. Running hot water.
All the mod cons.
I put in the plumbing myself.
A word a warning though.
Don't go wandering around here
in the middle of the night.
It's a real old building.
Lots of corridors.
Don't go nowhere.
Rotten floorboards.
You know what I mean?
Oh yeah.
And it is St.
Patrick's Day night.
You just might fall foul
of Darragh O'Donoghue's
rusty blade.
Good luck to you.
(door opens, closes)
- No way.
Absolutely not.
- Oh wait, let's consider this.
- I didn't mind coming here,
but I have not drunk
nearly enough whiskey
to agree to stay the night.
- Then why don't you
just drink some more?
Oops.
- [Kendra] You have certainly
had enough for both of us.
- I was just killing some
more bacteria for you.
- What do you think, Sian?
- Um, I dunno.
I don't much fancy
going out in the rain.
- Let's take a vote on it.
Who's okay with
staying the night?
- How come every time we
take a vote on something,
Leena gets her way?
- What can I say?
It's democracy.
America's gift to the world.
- Mr. O'Reilly?
Are you there?
(ominous music)
- [O'Reilly] Ah, there you are.
(bottle clanging)
(ominous music)
(paper rustling)
(O'Reilly laughing)
(paper ripping)
(thunder rumbling)
- [Kendra] I'm really,
really not happy about this.
- Oh, don't tell
me you're scared.
- [Kendra] Of what?
- The ghost.
What was his name again?
- Darragh O'Donoghue.
- Oh, yeah, him
stalking the corridors.
Him and his big tool.
- Shut up.
- I don't know where he's gone.
- Oh well, nevermind.
I mean, he said we
could stay, didn't he?
So why don't we
just find the rooms?
(ominous music)
- He said the rooms
were upstairs, right?
- You first.
- Why me?
You've got the torch.
Alright, fine.
(stairs creaking)
It's okay.
There's two doors up here and
a passage going the other way.
Wait down there a second, I'm
gonna go check out the rooms.
There's candles.
Anybody got a lighter?
- Oh, I do.
- I didn't know you smoked.
- Only in bed.
You know, afterwards.
- 30-a-day habit
if that's the case.
(ominous music)
- It's not too bad, actually.
- I'll take this room.
- Well, I'm with Leena.
I want to be near a torch
in case this all goes wrong.
- Looks like it's
just me and you then.
- Yeah. Okay.
- Come on then.
- Look, two beds.
At least we don't have to share.
- Thank God.
Sorry.
I mean, no offense, I just,
just like my own space.
What is all that junk?
- I have no idea.
This place must be a
gold mine for antiques.
- [Daisy] You
don't mind, do you?
- What?
- Sharing?
- Oh...
Only, there's not very
much choices, is there?
- I suppose not.
- So you gonna
get ready for bed?
- Oh, yeah, I was
just gonna wear this.
It's a bit chilly, isn't it?
- No.
Too hot, actually.
Must be all the candles.
- Or the whiskey.
- Yeah, or that.
This dress is just,
it's too tight.
- It looks amazing.
- Really?
You think so?
I can't wait to take
it off, actually.
Could you...
Could you undo me?
- What?
- Could you undo me?
It took me forever to
do it this morning.
- Oh, um, yeah, okay.
(mellow music)
- [Leena] Aren't you
gonna use the shower room?
- Well, I mean,
as much as I hate
to go to bed without a shower,
I doubt it would
get me much cleaner.
Everything in this
place is filthy.
- So what's that?
- This is my skincare routine
I start with this.
This goes on the face and
the hands for 10 minutes,
then I wash it off.
This one, this stays
on for 20 minutes.
I spritz with cold water
and then I finish with
an abrasive derma rub.
- I get the picture.
- Don't you have a
skincare routine?
- Soap and water.
Oh, no way.
- What is it?
- Do you know what this is?
This is a genuine Joseph
Manton flintlock pistol.
It's gotta be at
least 200 years old.
A pair of these came up
for auction a year ago,
they went for thousands.
- Well, I don't suppose
Mr. O'Reilly would notice
if you wanted to
take it with you.
- Come on, I wouldn't do that.
(dress unzips)
(mellow music)
- So what do you think?
- You're gorgeous.
- No, not about that.
About this place, about
the trip, about Dublin.
- Oh, it's nice.
- Only, I know it's not really
that good timing for you,
what with everything that
went on with your parents.
- That was nothing.
- But didn't they
threaten to disown you?
That can't have
been about nothing.
We, we spoke about it, actually.
Us three.
We were worried that
we might be forcing you
to come away with us.
- No, no.
I wanted to be here.
- There's bullets in here.
Ramrod.
What's this?
Gunpowder.
- Did you say it
was 200 years old?
- Well, Joseph Manton started
producing guns in 1780.
But this type is from
the early 1800's.
- It does fit with
O'Reilly's story then.
- What do you mean?
- Well, they shot
him, didn't they?
This Darragh O'Donoghue.
Then they buried
him under the floor.
So that could very
well be one of the guns
they used to kill him.
- Stop trying to freak me out.
That story was
bullshit for tourists.
- Thought you liked
ghost stories?
- Doesn't mean I believe them.
- Are you tired?
- Not really.
- Me neither.
I'm buzzing, actually.
Must be that whiskey.
That reminds me.
- What is that?
- Well, you said you were cold.
This will warm you right up.
It's neat vodka.
- Mm.
(Sian coughs)
- It's almost as
disgusting as the whiskey.
- Well, I wasn't really planning
on drinking it straight
from the flask.
- Mm.
- [Daisy] Are you
getting used to it?
- Mm-hmm.
- So lovely to see
you smile for once.
I know.
We should take a picture.
Hold that.
(camera clicks)
Oh, that's really nice.
I'll send it to you.
- Could you take one on mine?
- Yeah, sure.
Same again?
- Yeah.
(camera clicks)
There you go.
- Don't worry, I won't
share it anywhere.
- Why not?
- Because you're
in your underwear.
- Oh, there's plenty
worse pictures of me
out there doing the rounds.
- I wish I had your confidence.
- Listen, you know, you don't
have to keep it a secret.
Whatever it is, you can tell me.
- I just can't.
- Well.
Look, I went
through so much shit
with my parents growing
up, especially with my dad.
But lucky for me, he wasn't
really around all that much,
so that was a bonus.
- I just wanna forget about it.
Enjoy the weekend.
- I'm so glad you came.
It wouldn't be a girl's
weekend without you, Sian.
- Thank you.
I was really worried.
You know about being a downer.
Spoiling it for everyone else.
- No, don't be silly.
- We love you, Siannie.
- Siannie?
Nobody calls me that.
- Well, I do.
Ah, ah.
- Sorry.
- No.
No, no.
It was just a little
unexpected, that's all.
- It was the vodka.
I'm not used to it.
- Wait, Sian, please.
I'm not offended or anything.
- I'll leave you in peace, okay.
- I just didn't
realize that you...
(door closes)
Felt that way.
Shit.
♪ I've been dreaming
of the ocean ♪
♪ I've searching for
the Crimson Sky ♪
♪ I've been starving
my emotion ♪
♪ Looking at the ships go by ♪
♪ Somebody rows me
to where I belong ♪
♪ So many years, cause
it's kind of full ♪
♪ Somebody rows me
to where I belong ♪
♪ Said the drifter as
his world's gone by ♪
- I wonder what else is in here?
What are you hiding?
- Oh!
What are you doing?
- Sorry.
It's just dust.
- You know what dust is?
Dust is 70% dead
human skin cells.
Oh my God.
It's all over my face.
I've got Mr.
O'Reilly on my face.
- Geez. I'm sorry.
- I'm gonna have to have
a shower now after all.
- I think he said it
was down the hallway.
- I will find it.
(thunder rumbling)
(ominous music)
- [O'Reilly] Running hot water.
All the mod cons.
I put in the plumbing myself.
- Jesus.
(ominous music)
(faucet squeaks)
(shower running)
Not bad.
- [O'Reilly] Don't go
wandering around here
in the middle of the night.
(loud thud)
(ominous music)
They say that Darragh O'Donoghue
never did rest in peace.
(lock snaps)
(Sian gasps)
(ominous music)
- Sorry.
I didn't mean to scare you.
It's me, Connor, from the bar.
- What are you doing here?
- Well, I just
thought, you know,
me and your friend were
getting on pretty well
back there in the bar.
- How did you know
where we were?
- Ah, ah, the fella.
That fella you went
off with O'Reilly.
My boss says he owns this place.
He's quite well-known,
apparently.
A bit of a character,
they tell me.
- Yeah.
- So anyway, is
your friend around?
Daisy?
- Up the stairs, the
door on the left.
- Do you think it'd be all
right if I go up there?
- I'm sure she'd be
pleased to see you.
(knock on door)
- Oh, come in.
- Hi there.
- Oh, hey.
(loud creaking)
- Mr. O'Reilly?
(thunder rumbling)
(Sian screams)
- [Daisy] What are
you doing here?
- Well, you did promise
to give me your number.
- I did.
Wait, how did you find me?
- Your friend, downstairs.
She told me you were up here.
- Sian?
- Yeah.
The one doing Gender Studies.
- How was she?
- She didn't look happy
to see me, to be honest.
So anyway, I just
thought, you know,
me and you were
getting on pretty well
back there in the bar.
Before you ran out on me.
- Yeah.
I'm sorry about that.
- I just thought it'd be a shame
if I didn't get your number.
- My number?
Is that all you want?
(ominous music)
(O'Reilly laughing)
(Sian crying)
(shower running)
(ominous music)
(floor creaking)
(Darragh snarls)
- [Darragh] Nora.
(thunder rumbling)
(dramatic music)
- [Darragh] Nora.
(suspenseful music)
(shower running)
- "Marie Kent, 29,
and Doris Wayman, 25,
"were reported missing in Dublin
"last week on Saint
Patrick's Day."
"Sarah West, 18,
Diane Norris, 19,
"and Ian Morris, from
Newcastle, England,
"were all were last seen leaving
"a Saint Patrick's
Day celebration in
Dublin last Friday."
My God.
We're in trouble.
(shower running)
(ominous music)
(Darragh heavy breathing)
(shower running)
- [Darragh] Nora.
(Darragh growls)
(Kendra screaming)
(scythe stabbing)
(body thuds)
- Shit.
(knock on door)
- Quick, hide!
Er, who is it?
- [Leena] It's me. I
have to talk to you.
- Come in.
- Listen, I think we need
to get out of here...
Where's Sian?
- Oh, long story.
- Well, anyway, we need to
find her and get out of here.
- What are you talking about?
- It's O'Reilly.
I think he's up to something.
- Wait, I thought you liked him.
I know he's a bit weird, but,
you're the one who wanted
stay here in the first place.
- Yeah, well that was before.
Look, I found this book
and all these papers.
And it's like this whole
weird, creepy collection.
- It sounds like the room
I used to share with you.
- Oh, come on, I'm
serious, Daisy.
Like there was this story
about how his parents died
and he inherited this place.
- What's so bad about that?
- They were murdered!
- By O'Reilly?
- Well, it doesn't say
that, but no, listen,
there were all these headlines
about missing people in
Dublin going back years.
- Wait, let me
get this straight.
You want a pack up, go
halfway across town,
all because you got scared
by some newspaper clippings?
- Why don't we go
find Sian and Kendra
and take a vote on it?
- You always win on those votes.
- Can you think of a better way?
I'll be back when
I've found everyone.
(door closes)
- What do you think?
- It's none of my business.
I think you've got
some weird friends.
- Kendra.
Kendra, are you here?
(Leena gasps)
No signal. Shit!
Daisy!
It's Kendra.
- What?
- She's...
She's-
- She's what?
- She's dead.
That bastard,
O'Reilly killed her!
- That's impossible.
- Just get dressed
and come with me.
(Daisy gasps)
Now do you believe
we have a problem?
- What happened to her?
- O'Reilly. I'm sure of it.
He's got some sick routine
of bringing people down here
and murdering them.
He's even got a collection of
news clippings all about it.
He's a total fucking psycho.
- You're the one
that brought us here.
You're the one that
wanted to stay the night.
- We all voted, didn't we?
You and your fucking vote!
- I'm sorry.
I just...
I'm sorry.
- It's okay.
You're right.
I'm the one that
got us into this
and I'm gonna be the
one to get us out of it.
- What should we do?
Should we, should
we call the police?
- I've already tried,
there's no signal.
Just like O'Reilly said.
First we're gonna make you safe
and I'll go find Sian, okay?
You're gonna stay in your room.
You're gonna barricade the door.
Use furniture,
anything you can find.
Don't open the door for anybody
except me or Sian, okay?
- What about you?
I'll be fine.
I'll be armed.
- What the hell's going on?
- It's true.
Kendra's dead.
- What?
- Give my phone.
Oh shit.
- [Connor] What are you doing?
- We need to barricade the door!
Help me!
- Wait.
Hold on.
Someone's actually really dead?
- Yes!
- Jesus.
(suspenseful music)
Listen, I think I might be
in a bit over my head here.
- What?
- If it's a good time
you're after, I'm your man.
But this, this is crazy!
- Where are you going?
I need your help with this.
- I've got a wife and kid
back in Kilkenny, all right?
If I leave now, I might be
able to make the last train.
- You fucking bastard!
- I'm sorry.
I've gotta go.
See you around.
(door opens, closes)
(suspenseful music)
Which way did I come in now?
(stairs creaking)
(Darragh snarling)
(phone chiming)
Hello?
How are ya?
No, I'm not on the train, but
I'm on my way to the station.
(Darragh snarling)
Is she still awake?
Put her on.
Hiya, Maggie.
You're supposed to be in bed.
It's late, you know.
(Darragh snarling)
No, I can't come home now.
I'll be home in the morning
and then we'll go
walk the dog, okay?
Alright.
Kiss, kiss, now bye.
Bye.
- [Darragh] Nora.
(Connor grunting)
Nora.
(body thuds)
(thunder rumbling)
- Sian, are you there?
Sian?
Sian, are you here?
(air blowing)
(suspenseful music)
(barricade thuds)
(door opening)
Sian!
- Leena!
- Oh, thank God, I
thought you were dead.
Who did this to you?
- It was Mr. O'Reilly.
- [Darragh] Nora.
Nora.
- Don't worry, I'm gonna
get us out of here.
- How is everyone else?
- Daisy's still up in her room.
I told her to
barricade the door.
She'll be fine.
There's like a
million knots in this.
- Mr. O'Reilly grabbed me
at the bottom of the stairs
and took me down here.
- I know.
You're not the first one, he's
been doing this for years!
That sick bastard!
I know exactly what
he's been up to!
- Oh really?
What exactly is it
that I've been up to?
- [Darragh] Nora.
- You fucking psycho!
I found your
collection upstairs.
All those missing people.
- So what?
- So it's obvious!
You lure people here, you
convince them to stay the night
and then you murder them!
- I never murdered
anyone my whole life.
(metal clanging)
(Daisy heavy breathing)
- If you're not a killer
then why is my friend
tied up in your
stinking basement?
- I don't have to
explain anything to you.
- You better start trying.
(Mr. O'Reilly laughs)
- Well now, do you even
know how to work that thing?
- Historian, remember?
(gun clicks)
I can even tell you
the year it was made.
- [Darragh] Nora.
Nora.
- My conscience is clear.
I gave you fair warning
like I always do.
Ya can't say I didn't!
- Fair warning?
Of what?
- Of what goes on here!
Every year.
Saint Patrick's Day!
You chose to stay
the night here.
Well, that's on you, darlin'!
- What are you talking about?
- Him!
Darragh O'Donoghue!
(Daisy heavy breathing)
- [Darragh] Nora.
(ominous music)
- This is bullshit!
My friend's body is
upstairs in your shower
and you killed her!
- If someone's dead, it's
'cause of Darragh O'Donoghue.
If it wasn't for me, he'd
have killed dozens more.
- What are you talking about?
- Like I said, every year he
rises from his resting place,
that unconsecrated ground.
And every year I make damn sure
there's someone here
to satisfy his needs.
That's why I tied
your friend up.
Make it easy for him.
It's my Saint Patrick's
Day gift to him.
(slow footsteps)
(Darragh snarling)
(Daisy screaming)
(Daisy gasping)
(Darragh heavy breathing)
- This, this isn't possible!
- I thought you
knew your history.
You never read about those
graves in ancient Greece?
All those giant rocks
pinned down on the bones
so the dead didn't get
up and start walking.
- It's not really my period.
- Well I have!
And if you don't
believe me, fair enough.
Go on!
Untie your friend!
See what happens.
He'll kill her!
He'll kill you!
He'll kill me!
He'll kill everyone!
Just like he did my ma and pa!
(Darragh heavy breathing)
- He did what?
- It's like I told you,
this place has been in my
family for generations.
My great great great
grandfather, he was
there that night
when they gunned
Darragh O'Donoghue down
and buried him where he fell.
And ever since then, my
family have kept him here.
Satisfying his
lust for vengeance.
Keeping the city
safe, you might say.
- What about all
the people who died?
- A necessary sacrifice.
They all knew what they were
getting themselves in for, huh?
They all knew the story
of Darragh O'Donoghue,
just like you did.
None of my business
if you didn't believe
what I was telling you.
- Leena, please, just untie me!
- Right.
- You're gonna regret this.
You wanna know why he
killed my mom and pa, huh?
Because they forgot to leave
his St. Patrick's Day gift!
(loud thud)
(floor creaking)
- What was that sound?
- I told you.
(floor creaking)
I told you.
You better not try and stop him!
(floor creaking)
- [Darragh] Nora.
- Nora!
(Sian whimpering)
(Sian screaming)
- No!
(Darragh O'Donoghue grunts)
(Sian gasping)
Bastard!
- [Mr. O'Reilly] Leave him be!
(Sian gasping)
(O'Reilly grunts)
(Darragh snarling)
- Oh Jesus.
Stay away from me.
(Darragh O'Donoghue snarling)
I'm warning you!
(gun fires)
(Darragh growls)
Oh shit!
(Darragh heavy breathing)
(Darragh snarls)
- [Darragh] Nora.
(gun fires)
(Darragh snarls)
(Leena grunts)
- Fuck!
(Darragh growls)
- Nora.
- Happy Saint
Patrick's Day, fucker.
(gun fires)
(Darragh snarls)
(body thuds)
(scythe clangs)
(thunder rumbling)
(Leena heavy breathing)
Daisy.
Daisy!
(somber music)
(Leena gasps)
(door opens)
(siren blaring)
(Leena crying)
(thunder rumbling)
Don't you fucking rain on me!
Don't you dare
fucking rain on me!
I've had enough for one night!
(Leena crying)
(phone vibrates)
(phone chimes)
(mellow music)
(O'Reilly screaming)
Bastard!
(mellow music)
(ominous music)
- [All] Happy St. Patrick's Day!
- Ugh.
(ominous music)
(door thudding)
- [Darragh] Nora.
- It can't be.
- You're dead!
I killed you!
(Darragh growls)
(Leena gasps)
(bright music)
(door closes)
(upbeat music)
- [Darragh] Nora.